翻译: 阿华百合赛高 可乐是优推
电波字幕组  诚心诚译
官方网站:dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组
欢迎您的加入
校对: 史努比基 Nikki
后期: 可乐推熊桑 英俊君 Nikki
压制: 凯撒 英俊君
冰雪奇缘
♪Born of cold and winter air and mountain rain combining.♪
♪生于肃冬 风啸天寒 山雨摧袭 交融贯穿♪
♪This icy force both foul and fair.Has a frozen heart worth mining.♪
♪凝冰之力 好坏参半 凛凛冰心 为人采堪♪
♪So cut through the heart, cold and clear.♪
♪破取坚冰 澄冷晶莹♪
♪Strike for love and strike for fear.♪
♪为爱努力 战胜恐惧♪
♪See the beauty sharp and sheer.♪
♪方见其美 锋利透明♪
♪Split the ice apart and break the frozen heart.♪
♪切开冰块 破开冰川之心♪
♪Ha!Ho! Watch your step! Let it go!♪
♪哈 嚯 小心脚下 放开手♪
♪Beautiful! Powerful!♪
♪多美丽 多强大♪
♪Dangerous! Cold!♪
♪太危险 太寒冷♪
♪Ice has a magic can't be controlled.♪
♪寒冰魔力 无人可控♪
♪Stronger than one, stronger than ten♪
♪一人难抵 十人难御♪
♪Stronger than a hundred men!♪
♪百人之力也难取胜♪
♪Born of cold and winter air and mountain rain combining.♪
♪生于肃冬 风啸天寒 山雨摧袭 交融贯穿♪
♪This icy force both foul and fair♪
♪凝冰之力 好坏参半♪
♪has a frozen heart worth mining.♪
♪凛凛冰心 为人采堪♪
♪Cut through the heart, cold and clear.♪
♪破取坚冰 清冷晶莹♪
♪Strike for love and strike for fear.♪
♪为爱努力 战胜恐惧♪
♪There's beauty and there's danger here.♪
♪此中有美亦有险♪
♪Split the ice apart!♪
♪破开晶莹寒冰♪
♪Beware the frozen heart.♪
♪小心冰川之心♪
快点 Sven
Come on, Sven!
Elsa
Elsa. Psst
Elsa!
醒醒 醒醒 快醒醒
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
Anna 回去再睡会
Anna, go back to sleep.
睡不着 天醒了 我也醒了
I just can't. The sky's awake, so I'm awake,
我们就该一起玩了
so we have to play.
自己玩去
Go play by yourself.
要一起堆雪人吗
Do you want to build a snowman?
快点 快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
施魔法吧 施魔法吧
Do the magic! Do the magic!
准备好了吗
Ready?
嗯
Uhhm...
太厉害啦
This is amazing!
看这个
Watch this!
我是雪宝 我喜欢温暖的抱抱
Hi, I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs.
我爱你 雪宝
I love you, Olaf.
等等
Hang on.
接住我
Catch me!
接住了
Gotcha!
再来
Again!
等一下
Wait!
慢一点
Slow down!
Anna
Anna!
Anna?
妈妈 爸爸
Mama! Papa!
没事的 Anna 我在这儿
You ok, Anna. I Got you.
ELsa 你做了什么
Elsa, what have you done?
这已经失控了
This is getting out of hand!
这是个意外 对不起 Anna
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna.
她冷得像冰一样
She's ice cold.
我知道我们得去哪儿
I know where we have to go.
冰
Ice?
再快点 Sven
Faster, Sven!
Sven
Sven!
请帮帮我们
Please... Help!
帮帮我的女儿
My daughter!
是国王陛下
He is the king!
石头人
Trolls...?
嘘 我还想听呢
Shush. I'm trying to listen.
小可爱们 我要把你们留下
Cuties. I'm gonna keep you.
陛下
Your Majesty!
魔力是与生俱来还是被诅咒了
Born with the powers or cursed?
与生俱来 而且越来越强大
Born. And they're getting stronger.
真幸运 伤到的不是心
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
心很难改变
The heart is not so easily changed,
但头脑可以
But the head can be persuaded.
请您尽力而为
Do what you must.
我建议抹去所有魔法
I recommend we remove all magic,
保险起见 与魔法有关的记忆也是
even memories of magic to be safe...
不过别担心 我会把欢乐留下
But don't worry, I'll leave the fun.
她会没事的
She will be okay.
但她会忘记我有魔力吗
But she won't remember I have powers?
这样最好
It's for the best.
听我说 Elsa
Listen to me, Elsa,
你的魔力只会不断增强
your power will only grow.
这会带来美
There is beauty in it...
但也会带来危险
But also great danger.
你必须要学会控制
You must learn to control it.
恐惧是你的敌人
Fear will be your enemy.
不 我们会保护她 她能学会控制的 我肯定
No. We'll protect her. She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
在那之前
Until then,
我们会关闭城门 减少仆人
we'll lock the gates. We'll reduce the staff.
限制她与人民的接触
We will limit her contact with people,
不让人们知道她有魔力
and keep her powers hidden from everyone.
包括Anna
Including Anna.
Elsa
Elsa?
♪Do you want to build a snowman?♪
♪想要一起堆雪人吗♪
♪Come on let's go and play♪.
♪来吧 跟我一起玩♪
♪I never see you anymore. Come out the door.♪
♪我再也没见过你出门♪
♪It's like you've gone away.♪
♪就好像你已经离开♪
♪We used to be best buddies,♪
♪你我曾经多么亲密无间♪
♪and now we're not. I wish you would tell me why.♪
♪现在却不再相见 我多想知道为什么♪
♪Do you want to build a snowman?♪
♪想要一起堆雪人吗♪
♪It doesn't have to be a snowman♪
♪不堆雪人也可以呀♪
走开 Anna
Go away, Anna.
♪Okay bye.♪
♪好吧 再见♪
戴上手套就会好的 你看
The gloves will help. See...
藏起来
Conceal it.
别去想
Don't feel it.
- 别让别人看见  - 别让别人看见
- Don't let it show.  - Don't let it show.
♪Do you want to build a snowman?♪
♪想要一起堆雪人吗♪
♪Or ride our bike around the halls?♪
♪或者在大厅里骑车♪
♪I think some company is overdue...♪
♪曾经的玩伴都消失不见♪
♪I've started talking to the pictures on the walls.♪
♪我已开始跟墙上的画聊天♪
坚持住 贞德
Hang in there, Joan.
♪It gets a little lonely all these empty rooms.♪
♪独自面对空房间 真的有点孤单♪
♪Just watching the hours tick by.♪
♪看着时间滴答流逝♪
我很害怕 它越来越强大了
I'm scared. It's getting stronger.
沮丧只会雪上加霜
Getting upset only makes it worse.
冷静一点
Calm down.
不 别碰我 求你了
No. Don't touch me. Please.
我不想伤到你们
I don't want to hurt you.
两周后见
See you in two weeks.
一定要去吗
Do you have to go?
不会有事的 Elsa
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Elsa
Elsa?
♪Please, I know you're in there♪
♪求你了 我知道你听得见♪
♪People are asking where you've been,♪
♪人们都问你去哪了♪
♪They say have courage and I'm trying to...♪
♪他们说要坚强 我也在努力♪
♪I'm right out here for you. Just let me in.♪
♪我就在这里 请让我进去♪
♪We only have each other.♪
♪我们只有彼此了♪
♪It's just you and me.♪
♪只剩下你和我♪
♪What are we gonna do?♪
♪我们该怎么办♪
♪Do you want to build a snowman?♪
♪想要一起堆雪人吗♪
三年后
欢迎来到阿伦黛尔
Welcome to Arendelle!
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir!
小心脚下 城门马上就打开了
Watch your Steps please. The Gates Will be opening Soon.
我为什么要穿这个啊
Why do I have to wear this?
因为女王成年了
Because the Queen has come of age.
今天是加冕日
It's Coronation Day!
又不是我干的
That's not my fault.
你想干嘛 Sven
What do you want, Sven?
我要我的零食
Give me a snack!
要说什么来着
What's the magic word?
请
Please!
要懂得分享
A.. a... a... a! Share!
他们终于打开城门了
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
而且是一整天呢
And for a whole day!
快点 Persi
Faster, Persi!
阿伦黛尔 我们最神秘的贸易伙伴
Ah, Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
快开门吧 让我揭开你的秘密
Open those gates so I may unlock your secrets
攫取你的财富
and exploit your riches.
我是不是大声说出来了
Did I just say that out loud?
我等不及要
Oh, me sore eyes can't wait
去见女王和公主了
to see the Queen and the Princess.
她们一定可爱极了
I bet they're absolutely lovely.
她们肯定美极了
I bet they are beautiful.
Anna公主
Princess Anna...?
哈 怎么了
Huh? Yeah?
抱歉吵醒您 但是
Sorry to wake you, ma'am but...
不 不 没有
No, no, no. You didn't.
我起来好久了
I've been up for hours.
谁在门外
Who is it?
还是我 城门马上就要打开了
It's still me, ma'am. The gates will open soon.
该去做准备了
ime to get ready.
当然
Of course!
准备什么
Ready for what?
您姐姐的加冕礼
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
我姐姐的加冕礼
My sister's cor-neration...
今天是加冕日
It's coronation day!
♪The window is open! So's that door!♪
♪窗户都打开了 门也是♪
♪I didn't know they did that anymore.♪
♪我以为再也不会有这么一天♪
♪Who knew we owned 8000 salad plates...?♪
♪谁知道我们有8000个沙拉盘♪
♪For years I have roamed these empty halls♪
♪在这些空旷的大厅里我闲逛了好多年♪
♪Why have a ballroom with no balls?♪
♪为何只有舞厅却没有舞会♪
♪Finally, they're opening up the gates!♪
♪他们终于打开了城门♪
♪There'll be actual ,real, people♪
♪终于可以见到活生生的人♪
♪It'll be totally strange.♪
♪对我来说多么陌生♪
♪But wow am I so ready for this change!♪
♪而我有没有准备好这个大转变呢♪
♪For the first time in forever,♪
♪因为 在我生命中第一次♪
♪There'll be music, there'll be light.♪
♪拥有美妙音乐和灯光♪
♪For the first time in forever,♪
♪漫漫时光中第一次♪
♪I'll be dancing through the night.♪
♪尽情跳舞至天明♪
♪Don't know if I'm elated or gassy,♪
♪不知我是否高兴过头或是在吹嘘♪
♪But I'm somewhere in that zone♪
♪但也八九不离十♪
♪Cause for the first time in forever,♪
♪我生命中第一次♪
♪I won't be alone.♪
♪不再孤单一人♪
我等不及要见大家
I can't wait to meet everyone...
要是我遇到那个"他"呢
What if I meet "The one"?
♪Tonight, imagine me gown and all♪
♪今夜 我身着华服♪
♪Fetchingly draped against the wall.♪
♪靠在墙边 亭亭玉立♪
♪The picture of sophisticated grace.♪
♪那画面多么优雅♪
♪I suddenly see him standing there,♪
♪突然看见他站在那里♪
♪a beautiful stranger tall and fair.♪
♪英俊的陌生人挺拔潇洒♪
♪I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face!♪
♪我想要在嘴里塞满巧克力♪
♪But then we laugh and talk all evening,♪
♪然后一起放声大笑 彻夜聊天♪
♪Which is totally bizarre.♪
♪这多么奇怪啊♪
♪Nothing like the life I've led so far.♪
♪完全不同于从前♪
♪For the first time in forever,♪
♪我生命中第一次♪
♪There'll be magic, There'll be fun.♪
♪感受到魔法和欢乐♪
♪For the first time in forever,♪
♪我生命中第一次♪
♪I could be noticed by someone.♪
♪可以被一个人注意♪
♪And I know it is totally crazy♪
♪我知道期待浪漫邂逅♪
♪To dream I'd find romance.♪
♪是多么的疯狂又不切实际♪
♪But for the first time in forever,♪
♪但这是我生命中第一次♪
♪At least I've got a chance!♪
♪拥有这个机会♪
♪Don't let them in. Don't let them see.♪
♪别与人靠近 别被人发现♪
♪Be the good girl You always have to be.♪
♪就像从前 做个好女孩♪
♪Conceal. Don't feel.♪
♪隐藏好 别去想♪
♪Put on a show.♪
♪把戏演好♪
♪Make one wrong move and everyone will know.♪
♪出一点差错就人尽皆知♪
♪But it's only for today.♪
♪还好只是今天♪
♪It's only for today! It's agony to wait.♪
♪只是今天 等待太煎熬♪
♪It's agony to wait.♪
♪等待太煎熬♪
♪Tell the guards to open up the...♪
♪告诉守卫 打开♪
♪The gate!♪
♪城门♪
♪For the first time in forever.♪
♪我生命中第一次♪
♪Don't let them in don't let them see♪  - ♪I'm getting what I'm dreaming of.♪
- ♪别与人靠近 别被人发现♪  - ♪我得到梦寐以求的东西♪
♪Be the good girl you always have to be♪  - ♪A chance to change my only world♪
- ♪就像从前 做个好女孩♪  - ♪抓住改变命运的机会♪
♪Conceal.♪
♪藏好瞒住♪
♪A chance to find true love♪
♪寻找真爱♪
♪Conceal. Don't feel♪
♪藏好 别去感受♪
♪Don't Let them know.♪
♪别让他们知道♪
♪I know it all ends tomorrow,♪
♪我知道明天一切都会结束♪
♪So it has to be today!♪
♪今天是我唯一机会♪
♪Cause for the first time in forever...♪
♪因为今天是我生命中第一次♪
♪For the first time in forever!♪
♪我生命中第一次♪
♪Nothing's in my way!♪
♪不被干涉 随心所欲♪
嘿
Hey!
对不起 你受伤了吗
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
嘿
Hey!
没有 我没事
I-ya, no. No. I'm okay.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
没事 我刚才没看路
Yeah, I just wasn't looking where I was going.
但是我没事
But I'm great, actually.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
Hans王子 来自南艾尔斯
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
阿伦黛尔的Anna公主
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
公主
Princess...?
失礼了
My Lady.
你好 又来了
Hi... again.
伙计
Oh boy.
真丢人 不是你丢人
Ha. This is awkward. Not you're awkward,
只是我们 我很丢人
but just because we're... I'm awkward.
你很帅 等等 啥
You're gorgeous. Wait, what?
我向阿伦黛尔的公主正式道歉
I'd like to formally apologize for
我的马撞到您了
hitting the Princess of Arendelle with my horse...
以及之后的一切 都很抱歉
And for every moment after.
不 不 不 没事的 我不是"那位"公主
No. No-no. It's fine. I'm not THAT Princess.
要是你撞了我姐姐Elsa 就
I mean, if you'd hit my sister Elsa, that would be...
因为 你知道的
'Cuz, you know...
你好
Hello.
你真幸运 撞的是我而已
But, lucky you, it's-it's just me.
是你而已
Just you?
钟声 加冕礼
The bells. The coronation.
我 我
I... I...
我得走了 我 我得走了
I better go. I have to go, I better go.
拜
Bye!
陛下 您的手套
Your Majesty, the gloves.
在此圣地
Sehm hon hell drr in-um hell-gum Ayg-num ok
冠冕权杖 皆授予尔
krund ee thes-um hellgah Stahth, ehk teh frahm fur-ear Uthear...
阿伦黛尔的Elsa女王
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
阿伦黛尔的Anna公主
Princess Anna of Arendelle!
这吗 你确定 我觉得我不该
Here? Are you sure? I do not think I suppose to...
好吧
Okay
嗨
Hi.
跟我说嗨吗 噢 嗨
Hi me...? Oh. Um. Hi.
你很美
You look beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你更美腻 不 不是腻
You look beautifuller. I mean, not fuller.
你不腻 是更美丽
You don't look fuller, but more beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
原来这就是舞会
So, this is what a party looks like?
比我想的更热闹
It's warmer than I thought.
这是什么味道 这么香
And what is that amazing smell?
- 巧克力  - 巧克力
- Chocolate. - Chocolate.
陛下 猥琐屯公爵
Your Majesty. The Duke of Weaseltown.
是维斯顿 维斯顿公爵
Weselton. The Duke of Weselton..
陛下
Your Majesty,
作为您最密切的贸易伙伴
As your closest partner in trade,
看来您成为女王以后的第一支舞
It seems only fitting that I offer you
由我来邀请您跳是再合适不过了
Your first dance as queen.
谢谢你 只是我不跳舞
Thank you... Only I don't dance.
但我妹妹跳哦
But my sister does.
你真幸运
Lucky you...
我不觉得
Oh, I don't think...
你要是觉得晕就告诉我 我会接住你的
If you swoon, let me know, I'll catch you.
抱歉啦
Sorry.
简直像只敏捷的孔雀
Like an agile peacock...
话说 城门开了真是好啊
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
为什么起初要关上呢
Why did they shut them in the first place?
你知道吗
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
不知道
No.
No..
好吧 等一下
Oh, all right. Hang on.
我"小水鸟"的名号可不是白来的
They don't call me "The little dipper" For nothing.
我如猴面公鸡一般飞舞
Like a chicken... with the face of a monkey... I fly.
你要是还想跳就告诉我哦 小姐
Let me know when you're ready for another round, M'Lady.
他可真能蹦跶
Well, he was sprightly.
还是穿着高跟鞋呢
Especially for a man in heels.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
再好不过了
I've never been better.
这太棒了
This is so nice.
真希望能一直这样下去
I wish it could be like this all the time.
我也是
Me too...
但是不行
But it can't.
为什么 如果
Why not? If...
就是不行
It just can't.
抱歉 失陪一下
Excuse me for a minute.
还好我抓住你了
Glad I caught you.
Hans
Hans!
我常一个人在大厅里这样滑 抱歉
I often had the whole parlor to myself to slide... Oops. Sorry.
我敢说也是因为你的体型
Your physique helps I'm sure too.
这是什么
What's this?
我生来就有的
I was born with it,
虽然我梦见是被地精亲了
Although I dreamt I was kissed by a troll.
我喜欢
I like it.
对 一口吃掉 没错
Yeah, The whole thing! You got it.
好了 等下 你有几个兄弟
Okay wait, wait. So you have how many brothers?
十二个哥哥
Twelve older brothers.
有三个当我是空气
Three of them pretended I was invisible...
整整两年
literally... for two years.
太可怕了
That's horrible.
兄弟之间都这样
It's what brothers do.
姐妹也是
And sisters.
Elsa和我小时候很亲密
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
但是后来有一天 她就不理我了
But then, one day she just shut me out, and...
我都不知道为什么
And I never knew why.
我永远不会不理你
I would never shut you out.
我可以说句疯话吗
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
我喜欢疯话
I love crazy.
♪All my life has been a series of doors in my face.♪
♪我的生活像是眼前一连串的门♪
♪And then suddenly I bump into you.♪
♪然后我突然遇见你♪
我在想同样的事 因为就好像
I was thinking the same thing, because like...
♪I've been searching my whole life to find my own place.♪
♪我一生都在寻找属于自己的地方♪
♪And maybe it's the party talking,♪
♪也许是聚会闲聊♪
♪Or the chocolate fondue.♪
♪或是巧克力火锅♪
♪- But with you... - But with you...♪
♪- 但是和你在一起  - 但是和你在一起♪
♪I found my place.♪
♪我找到了自己的归宿♪
♪I see your face.♪
♪我看见了你的脸♪
♪And it's nothing like I've ever known before.♪
♪与过去完全不同♪
♪Love is an open... door!♪
♪爱情是扇敞开的门♪
- ♪Love is an open... door..♪. - ♪Door...♪
- ♪爱情是扇敞开的门♪  - ♪门♪
♪Love is an open... door...♪
♪爱情是扇敞开的门♪
♪With you! With you!♪
♪和你在一起 和你在一起♪
♪Love is an open door.♪
♪爱情是扇敞开的门♪
- ♪I mean it's crazy.♪ - ♪What?♪
- ♪这很疯狂♪  - ♪什么♪
♪We finish each other's...♪
♪我们吃完彼此的♪
♪Sandwiches!♪
♪三明治
♪That's what I was gonna say!♪
♪我正要说这个♪
♪I've never met someone... Who thinks so much like me.♪
♪我从未遇见某个人 想法和我如此像♪
两个人碰巧说出同一句话时 先喊出Jinx的人会让对方倒霉
♪Jinx... jinx again.
♪倒霉的是你 倒霉的还是你♪
♪Our Mental Synchronization Can have but one explanation,♪
♪我们心思一致 只有一种解释♪
♪You and I were just meant to be.♪
♪你和我是命中注定♪
- ♪Say goodbye.♪ - ♪Say goodbye.♪
- ♪说再见♪  - ♪说再见♪
♪To the pain of the past.♪
♪和过去的痛苦说再见♪
♪We don't have to feel it anymore!♪
♪因为我们不会再被伤害♪
♪Love is an open... door!♪
♪爱情是扇敞开的门♪
♪Love is an open door!♪
♪Life can be so much more... with you!♪
♪生活多么精彩 和你一起
♪With you!♪
♪和你一起
♪Love is an open... door.♪
♪爱情是扇敞开的门♪
我能说句疯话吗
Can I say something crazy...?
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
我能说句更疯狂的吗
Can I just say something even crazier?
我愿意
Yes.
请原谅 抱歉 我们可以直接绕过你吗
Oops! Pardon. Sorry. Can we just get around you there?
谢谢你 她在这
Thank you. Oh, there she is.
Elsa 我是说 女王
Elsa! I mean... Queen...
还是我 请允许我介绍
Me again. May I present,
来自南艾尔斯的Hans王子
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
我们希望 您能祝福
We would like... your blessing...
我们的婚姻
of... our marriage!
婚姻
Marriage...?
是的
Yes!
对不起 我不太明白
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
我们还没想好全部的细节
Well, We haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
我们需要几天来策划婚礼
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
肯定要有汤
Of course we'll have soup,
烤肉 冰淇淋和
roast, and ice cream and then...
等一下 我们住在哪
Wait. Would we live here?
这里么
Here?
当然
Absolutely!
Anna
Anna...
我们可以邀请你的十二个兄弟和我们住在一起  - 什么
Oh, we can invite all twelve of your brothers to stay with us...  - What?
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
肯定住得下 我不知道 可能有几个得要  - 等下
Of course we have the room. I don't know. Some of them must  - wait
慢一点
Slow down.
谁的兄弟都不可以待在这儿
No one's brothers are staying here.
你们也不可以结婚
No one is getting married.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
我能和你谈谈吗 单独谈谈
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
不 不论你要说什么
No. Whatever you have to say, you...
你可以对我们俩一起说
you can say to both of us.
好吧 你不能嫁给一个刚刚认识的男人
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
如果是真爱就可以
You Can if it's true love.
Anna 你知道什么是真爱吗
Anna, what do you know about true love?
比你知道的多 你只知道把别人拒之门外
More than you. All you know is how to shut people out.
你希望我能祝福你们 但是我不会
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
不好意思 我要走了
Now, Excuse me.
女王陛下 如果我能让您
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
你不能 我想你可以走了
No, you may not. And I-I think you should go.
聚会结束了 关闭城门
The party is over. Close the gates.
遵命 女王陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
什么 Elsa 不 等等
What? Elsa, no. No, wait!
把我的手套给我
Give me my glove!
Elsa 求你了 我不能再这样生活了
Elsa, please. Please. I can't live like this anymore.
那就离开
Then leave.
我到底对你做了什么
What did I ever do to you?!
够了 Anna
Enough, Anna.
不 为什么 为什么你拒我于门外
No. Why? Why do you shut me out?!
为什么你把世界拒于门外
Why do you shut the world out?!
你到底在怕什么
What are you so afraid of?!
我说 够了
I said, enough!
妖术 我就知道这里
Sorcery. I knew there was
有什么东西不对劲
something dubious going on here.
Elsa
Elsa...?
她在这
There she is.
女王陛下 女王万岁 Elsa女王
Your Majesty! Long live the Queen! Queen Elsa...
和我们一起饮酒吧
Come drink with us.
是她 Elsa女王
Yes,it is her. Queen Elsa.
女王陛下 您还好吗
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
她在这 拦住她
There she is! Stop her!
请你们离远点
Please, just stay away from me.
走开
Stay away!
怪物 怪物
Monster... Monster!
Elsa
Elsa!
Elsa...
等一下
Wait, please!
Elsa 停下
Elsa, stop!
Anna
Anna!
不要
No.
峡湾
The fjord.
下雪了
Snow?
是雪吗
是雪
Yes, snow!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
不
No.
你之前知道吗
Did you know?
不
No.
看 下雪了 下雪了
Look! It's snowing! It's snowing!
女王诅咒了这座岛
The Queen has cursed this land!
必须有人阻止她
She must be stopped!
你一定要找到她
You have to go after her.
等等 不
Wait, no!
你 你是不是也会妖术
You! Is there sorcery in you, too?
你也是个怪物吗
Are you a monster, too?
不是 我很普通
No. No. I'm completely ordinary.
没错
That's right she is.
最美的普通
In the best way.
我姐姐不是个怪物
And my sister's not a monster.
她差点杀了我
She nearly killed me.
你在冰上滑到了
You slipped on ice.
她造的冰
Her ice!
这是个意外 她当时很害怕
It was an accident. She was scared.
她不是故意的 这都不是她故意的
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this...
是我的错 是我给了她压力
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
所以该我去找她
So I'm the one that needs to go after her.
什么  - 是的
- What? - Yeah.
请把我的马牵来
Bring me my horse, please.
Anna 不行 这太危险了
Anna, no. It's too dangerous.
Elsa不危险
Elsa's not dangerous.
我会带她回来 我会让一切都好起来
I'll bring her back, And I'll make this right.
我和你一起去
I'm coming with you.
不
No.
我需要你留在这里治理阿伦黛尔
I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
我以荣誉起誓
On my honor.
我委托Hans王子在此负责
I leave Prince Hans in charge!
你确定你可以信任她吗
Are you sure you can trust her?
我不希望你受伤
I don't want you getting hurt.
她是我姐姐
She's my sister,
她永远不会伤害我
She would never hurt me.
♪The Snow glows white on the mountain tonight,♪
♪今夜白雪将山峦覆盖♪
♪Not a footprint to be seen.♪
♪将那足迹 掩埋♪
♪A kingdom of isolation♪
♪在这孤寂的国度♪
♪And it looks like I'm the queen.♪
♪我是这里的女王♪
♪The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside.♪
♪狂风暴雪 正如我此刻的心境♪
♪Couldn't keep it in, Heaven knows I tried...♪
♪无法再压抑 我已倾全力♪
♪Don't let them in, Don't let them see,♪
♪别与人靠近 别被发现♪
♪Be the good girl you always have to be.♪
♪就像从前 做个好女孩♪
♪Conceal, Don't feel, Don't let them know.♪
♪藏好 别去想 不能被发现♪
♪Well, Now they know.♪
♪可事与愿违♪
♪Let it go. Let it go.♪
♪随它吧 随它吧♪
♪Can't hold you back anymore.♪
再无法回到从前♪
Let it go. Let it go.♪
♪随它吧 随它吧♪
Turn away and Slam the door.♪
♪关上门了无牵挂♪
♪I don't care what they're going to say.♪
♪蜚语流言 何必在意♪
♪Let the storm rage on.♪
♪任风雪肆虐♪
♪The cold never bothered me anyway.♪
♪反正冰天雪地 我从不怕♪
♪It's funny how some distance makes everything seem small.♪
♪远远望去 一切都随着离开变得那么渺小♪
♪And the fears that once controlled me♪
♪曾控制着我的恐惧♪
♪Can't get to me at all.♪
♪我已成功逃离♪
♪It's time to see what I can do,♪
♪是时候看看什么是我所能及♪
♪To test the limits and Break through.♪
♪找到极限 突破自己♪
♪No right, No wrong, No rules for me...♪
♪没有对错 没有规矩♪
♪I'm free!♪
♪我自由了♪
♪Let it go! Let it go!♪
♪随它吧 随它吧♪
♪I am one with the wind and sky.♪
♪风和天空与我同在♪
♪Let it go! Let it go!♪
♪随它吧 随它吧♪
You'll never see me cry.♪
♪你不会看到我哭泣♪
♪Here I stand and...♪
♪我站在这♪
♪Here I'll stay.♪
♪我留在这♪
♪Let the storm rage on...♪
♪任风雪肆虐♪
♪My power flurries through the air into the ground.♪
♪我的力量激荡空气进入大地♪
♪My soul is spiraling in frozen fractals all around.♪
♪我的灵魂随四周冰片盘旋而上♪
♪And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast...♪
♪一思一念都如一阵冰风化为结晶♪
♪I'm never going back,♪
♪我绝不会回去♪
♪the past is in the past!♪
♪过去的事已经过去♪
♪Let it go! Let it go!♪
♪随它吧 随它吧♪
♪And I'll rise like the break of dawn.♪
♪我会像破晓的曙光一样升起♪
♪Let it go! Let it go!♪
♪随它吧 随它吧♪
♪That perfect girl is gone.♪
♪那个完美的女孩已不在♪
♪Here I stand in the light of day.♪
♪我站着 沐浴在这白昼之光♪
♪Let the storm rage on!♪
♪任风雪肆虐♪
♪The cold never bothered me anyway.♪
♪反正冰天雪地 我从不怕♪
Elsa Elsa
Elsa! Elsa!
Elsa 是我 Anna
Elsa, It's me, Anna...
我不是故意要让你把夏天变成冰天雪地的
Your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
我错了 这都是我的错
I'm sorry. It's all my f-f-fault.
当然 如果她之前就告诉了我
Of course, none of this would have happened
根本就不会有这一出
if she'd just told me her secret... ha...
她这个混蛋
She's a stinker.
不要 回来 别跑
Oh no. No. No. No. Come back. No.
好吧
Oooo-kay
雪 非得要是雪
Snow, it had to be snow,
她会的就不能是热带的魔法
She couldn't have had tr-tr-tropical magic
用白沙覆盖海湾 还有温暖的
that covered the f-f-fjords in white sand and warm...
火
Fire! Whoa!
Oaken的流浪交易站
Wandering Oaken's Trading Post.
以及桑拿
Ooh! And sauna...
夏季大酬宾
Big summer blow out.
泳衣和木底鞋半价
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
还有我自制的防晒霜
And a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
现在的靴子呢
For now, how about boots,
好吧
Oh, great.
冬靴和冬衣
Winter boots... and dresses?
在我们的冬季区
That would be in our winter department.
我想问问 有没有年轻女子
Oh. Um, I was just wondering; has another young woman,
女王什么的 刚好经过这
The Queen perhaps, I don't know, passed through here?
只有你会疯到在这种暴风雪天里出门 亲爱的
Only one crazy enough to be out in this storm is you, dear.
你和这个家伙
You and this fellow... Hoo hoo.
夏季大酬宾
Big summer blow out.
胡萝卜
Carrots.
啊
Hah?
你挡着了
Behind you.
哦 抱歉
Oh, right. Excuse me.
这七月里好大的一场暴风雪啊
A real howler in July, Yes?
是从哪里来的呢
Where ever could it be coming from?
从北峰
The North Mountain.
北峰
North Mountain.
一共四十
That'll be forty.
四十 不行 十块
Forty? No, ten.
亲爱的 这可不行
Oh dear, that's no good. See
这些是我们的冬季库存
These are from our winter stock,
供求很紧张的
where supply and demand have a big problem.
你和我谈供求
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
我是靠卖冰谋生的
I sell ice for a living.
这生意现在可不好做啊
Ooh, that's a rough business to be in right now.
我是说 那真的很
I mean, that is really...
很不幸
Ahem. That's unfortunate.
还是四十块 但是我可以免费赠送
Still forty. But I will throw in a
一次Oaken的桑拿
visit to Oaken's sauna. Hoo hoo!
嗨 亲爱的家人们
Hi, family.
我只有十块 帮个忙吧
Ten's all I got. Help me out.
十块我只能给你这些
Ten will get you this and no more.
好吧 我只想知道一件事
Okay, just tell me one thing. What was
北峰那边发生了什么
happening on the North Mountain?
看起来像是有魔法吗
Did it seem magical?
是的 闪一边去
Yes! Now, back up
我还要和这个无赖讨价还价呢
while I deal with this crook here.
你叫我什么
What did you call me?
好了 好了 我
Okay. Okay, I'm-Ow! Whoa!
拜拜
Bye bye.
不 Sven 我没弄到胡萝卜
No Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
但是我找到了我们俩睡觉的地方
But I did find us a place to sleep.
免费的
And it's free.
我为这件暴力事件道歉
I'm sorry about this violence.
我给你加一夸脱的碱鳕鱼
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
作为补偿
So We'll have good feelings.
就只要衣服和靴子
Just the outfit and boots, yah?
♪Reindeers are better than people.♪
♪驯鹿比人更好♪
♪Sven, Don't you think that's true?♪
♪Sven 你也觉得吧♪
♪Yeah, People will beat you and curse you and cheat you.♪
♪人会打你骂你欺骗你♪
♪Every one of em's bad, Except you.♪
♪每个人都很坏 除了你♪
♪Oh, Thanks, Buddy.♪
♪谢谢 兄弟♪
♪But People smell better than Reindeers.♪
♪但是人比驯鹿好闻♪
♪Sven, Don't you think I'm right?♪
♪Sven 你觉得我说得对吗♪
♪That's once again true, for all except you♪
♪说得没错 除了你♪
♪You got me. ♪Let's call it a night.♪
♪你赢了 ♪今晚就到这里♪
♪Good night.♪
♪晚安♪
♪Don't let the Frostbite bite.♪
♪可别被冻伤♪
不错的对唱啊
Nice duet.
是你啊
Oh, it's just you.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想让你带我去北峰
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
我不给人带路
I don't take people places.
我再说一遍
Let me rephrase that...
带我去北峰
Take me up the North Mountain...
拜托
Please.
我知道怎么让这冬天停下
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
我们黎明出发
We leave at dawn...
你忘了给Sven的胡萝卜
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
抱歉 抱歉 对不起 我不是
Oops. Sorry. Sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
我们现在就走 马上
We leave now. Right now.
抓紧 我们要加快速度了
Hang on! We like to go fast!
我喜欢加速
I like fast!
哇 哇啊 把你的脚拿下去 刚上的漆
Whoa, whoa! Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
你是来自乡下么
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
不 我是在城堡里长大的
Ew. No, I was raised in a castle.
那告诉我 这冰天雪地的是女王发了什么疯
So tell me, what made the Queen go all ice-crazy?
这是我的错
Oh well, it was all my fault.
我订了婚 她很生气 因为
I got engaged but then she freaked out because...
我那天刚认识他
I'd only just met him, you know, that day.
她说她不会祝福这段婚姻
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage...
等下 你和一个刚认识的男人订婚了
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met that day?
是的 总之 我生气了 她也生气了
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad and so she got mad
她想要走
and then she tried to walk away,
然后我抓住了她的手套
and I grabbed her glove...
等一下 你是想告诉我
Hang on. You mean to tell me
你和一个刚认识的男人订婚了
you got engaged to someone you just met that day?
没错 好好听 问题是
Yes. Pay attention. But the thing is...
她一直戴着手套
she wore the gloves all the time,
所以我想 也许她有洁癖呢
So I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
你的父母没有告诉过你要提防陌生人吗
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
是 他们说过
Yes, they did...
但是Hans不是陌生人
But Hans is not a stranger.
是吗 他姓什么
Oh yeah? What's his last name?
南艾尔斯的
Of-the-Southern-Isles?
他最喜欢什么食物
What's his favorite food?
三明治
Sandwiches.
最好朋友的名字
Best friend's name?
John吧
Probably John.
眼睛颜色
Eye color.
梦幻
Dreamy.
鞋码
Foot size?
鞋码不重要
Foot size doesn't matter.
你和他一起吃过饭吗
Have you had a meal with him yet?
万一你讨厌他吃东西的样子呢
What if you hate the way he eats?
如果你讨厌他挖鼻孔的样子呢
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
挖鼻孔
Picks his nose?
然后吃掉
And eats it.
抱歉 他可是位王子
Excuse me, sir. He's a prince.
男人都一样
All men do it.
这不重要 我们是真爱
Look it doesn't matter, it's true love.
听起来可不像真爱
Doesn't sound like true love.
你是什么爱情专家吗
Are you some sort of love expert?
不是 但我的朋友是
No. But I have friends who are.
你的朋友是爱情专家
You have friends who are love experts?
我才不信
I'm not buying it
别说话
Stop talking.
不不不 我倒想见见你那些
No, no, no. I'd like to meet these...
不 我说真的
No, I mean it.
嘘
Ssshhh.
Sven 快 走
Sven, go. Go!
那是什么
What are they?
狼群
Wolves.
Wolves?
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
我来搞定
I've got this.
你只要别掉下去被吃了就行
You just... don't fall off and don't get eaten.
但是我想帮忙
But I wanna help.
不行
No.
为什么不行
Why not?
你做的决定我信不过
Because I don't trust your judgment.
你说什么
Excuse me?!
谁会嫁给一个刚认识的男人
Who marries a man she just met?
这是真爱
It's true love!
Christopher
Christopher!
是Kristoff
It's Kristoff!
低头
Duck!
你差点把我点着了
You almost set me on fire!
但是我没有
But I didn't.
准备跳过去 Sven
Get ready to jump, Sven!
用不着你来跟他说干什么
You don't tell him what to do!
我来
I do!
跳 Sven
Jump, Sven!
我刚把贷款付清
But I just paid it off.
不 不 不
Uh-oh. No, no, no.
抓住
Grab on!
快拉 Sven 快拉
Pull, Sven! Pull!
你的雪橇和里面的东西我都会赔你的
I'll replace your sled and everything in it.
如果你不想再帮我了 我完全理解
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
我当然不想再帮她了
Of course I don't want to help her anymore.
事实上 这件事让我
In fact, this whole thing has ruined me
以后都不会再帮任何人了
For helping anyone ever again.
但是放她一个人她会死的
But she'll die on her own.
我不在乎
I can live with that.
但是她死了就没人赔你新雪橇了
But you won't get your new sled if she's dead.
有时候我真讨厌你
You know sometimes I really don't like you.
等等 我们来了
Hold up. We're coming.
真的么
You are?!
我是说 当然 跟着吧
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
是阿伦黛尔
Arendelle.
一片冰天雪地
It's completely frozen.
没事的 Elsa会融化这冰雪的
But it'll be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
她会么
Will she?
当然
Yeah.
好了 北峰是这边吗
Now come on. This way to the North Mountain?
这边才对
More like this way.
我以前都不知道冬天能这么美
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
没错 真是太美了 不是么
Yeah! It really is beautiful, isn't it?
但就是太白了
But it's so white.
增添点色彩就更好了
You know, how about a little color?
来点深红色 或者黄绿色点缀一下
I'm thinking like maybe some crimson, chartreuse...
黄色怎么样 不 还是算了
How about yellow... no, not yellow.
黄色搭配白雪 呃 算了吧
Yellow and snow? Brrrr... no go.
我说的对么
Am I right?
你好
Hi!
你好诡异
You're creepy.
别给我
I don't want it!
还给你
Back atchya!
拜托别再丢着我玩了 只是个头而已
Please don't drop me, Come on, it's just a head.
别给我
No
好吧
All right
我们这头可开的不算好
we got off to a bad start.
噢 身子
Ew, ew, the body!
等下 怎么回事儿
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
为什么你们都和蝙蝠似的倒悬着
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
好吧 等下
Alright. Wait one second.
谢谢你
Oooh! Thank you!
不客气
You're welcome.
现在才完美嘛
Now I'm perfect.
差一点儿
Well, almost.
刚才就好像我整个人都上下颠倒了
It was like my whole life got upside down.
用力过头了 对不起 我只是
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry! I was just...
呼 头有点晕
Woo! Head rush!
你还好么
Are you okay?
开什么玩笑 从没这么好过
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
我一直想要个鼻子
I've always wanted a nose.
真可爱 就像个小独角兽似的
So cute. It's like a little baby unicorn.
怎么 哇哦
What? Hey! Whoa.
现在更喜欢了
Oh, I love it even more! Hah...
好了 让我们重新认识下
All right, let's start this thing over.
你们好 我叫雪宝 我喜欢温暖的抱抱
Hi everyone. I'm Olaf. And I like warm hugs.
雪宝
Olaf?
没错 雪宝
That's right, Olaf.
那你是
And you are?
我叫Anna
Oh, um... I'm Anna.
那这个滑稽的笨驴是谁
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
它叫Sven
That's Sven.
那这头驯鹿叫什么
Uh-huh. And who's the reindeer?
Sven
Sven.
那他们 好吧 这样记起来还容易点
Oh. They're... oh, okay... Makes things easier for me.
看呀 它想亲人家的鼻子
Ha. Aw, look at him tryin' to kiss my nose.
我也很喜欢你啦
I like you, too!
雪宝 是Elsa把你造出来的吗
Olaf, did Elsa build you?
没错 怎么了
Yeah. Why?
你知道她在哪吗
Do you know where she is?
知道 怎么了
Yeah. Why?
你能带我们去找她吗
Do you think you could show us the way?
可以 怎么了
Yeah. Why?
这玩意是怎么回事
How does this work?
够了 Sven 我在说事儿呢
Stop it, Sven. Trying to focus here.
可以 怎么了
Yeah, Why?
我告诉你怎么了
I'll tell you Why.
我们需要Elsa把夏天带回来
We need Elsa to Bring back summer.
夏天
Summer?
没错
Uhum.
不知道为什么 但是
Oh, I don't know why but
我真的很喜欢夏天这个想法
I've always loved the idea of summer,
有太阳 还有其他温暖的东西
And Sun, and all things hot.
真的么
Really?
你大概对高温没什么概念吧
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
我没有
Nope!
但是有时我会闭上双眼
But sometimes I like to close my eyes
想象夏日降临会是什么样
and imagine what it'd be like when summer does come.
♪Bees'll buzz, Kids'll blow dandelion fuzz.♪
♪蜜蜂嗡嗡 孩子们吹散蒲公英♪
♪And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer.♪
♪冰雪在夏日做什么 我就做什么♪
♪A drink in my hand, my snow up against the burning sand.♪
♪饮料在手中 热沙在身下 ♪
♪Probably getting gorgeously tanned in summer.♪
♪或许还能晒成古铜色♪
♪I'll finally see a summer breeze,♪
♪我终能感受到夏日清风♪
♪blow away a winter storm♪
♪是如何吹走冬季的风暴♪
♪and find out what happens to♪
♪当天气暖洋洋♪
♪solid water, When it gets warm.♪
♪坚冰会变成怎样♪
♪And I can't wait to see, what my buddies all think of me.♪
♪我迫不及待想知道小伙伴们会怎样看我♪
♪Just imagine how much cooler I'll be in summer!♪
♪想想炎炎夏日里我该会有多酷♪
♪The hot and the cold are both so intense,♪
♪高温和寒冷都太强烈♪
♪Put 'em together, It just makes sense!♪
♪让冰火相融 该多么美好♪
♪Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle,♪
♪冬天是缩成一团互相取暖的好时间♪
♪But put me in summer and I'll be a...♪
♪但当我身处夏日 我就会成为一个♪
♪Happy Snowman!♪
♪开心的雪人♪
♪When life gets rough I like to hold on to my dream♪
♪每当日子不太好过 我就幻想自己身处夏日♪
♪of relaxing in the summer sun just letting off steam!♪
♪冒点蒸汽 放松身心♪
♪Oh the sky will be Blue...♪
♪天空如此湛蓝♪
♪And you guys'll be there too.♪
♪你们也会在身边♪
♪When I finally do what frozen things do in summer!♪
♪当我终于能做冰雪在夏日做的事♪
我要跟他说实话
I'm gonna tell him.
你敢
Don't you dare.
♪In summer!♪
♪在夏日♪
来吧 Elsa在这边
So, Come on! Elsa's this way.
让我们把夏天带回来吧
Let's go bring back summer!
我来了
I'm coming!
总得有人告诉它实话吧
Somebody's got to tell him.
不对 不对 必须得背面朝下
No. No. You've got the bark facing down.
背面朝上放才对
The bark needs to be face-up.
朝下放不容易受潮
Bark down is drier.
朝上放
Bark up.
朝下
Bark down.
大衣 有人需要大衣吗
Cloak. Does anyone need a cloak?
阿伦黛尔欠您恩情 王子殿下
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
城堡已经开放了 大礼堂里有热汤
The castle is open. There's soup
和热格拉格(一种混合了葡萄酒及糖与香料的瑞典式热饮)
and hot glogg in the Great Hall.
拿着 把这些分发下去
Here. Pass these out.
Hans王子 我们就这样
Prince Hans, are we just
坐在这里挨冻
expected to sit here and freeze
看着你把阿伦黛尔的贸易物资都给送出去吗
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
Anna公主授意我
Princess Anna has given her orders and...
这不是一回事
And that's another thing!
你还没明白过来吗
Has it dawned on you that
你的公主搞不好现在正在和妖女密谋
your princess may be conspiring with a wicked sorceress...
要灭掉我们所有人
to destroy us all?
不准怀疑公主 她把我留在这里负责
Do not question the Princess. She left me in charge,
我对于意图谋反之人可是毫不手软的
and I will not hesitate to protect Arendelle from treason.
谋反
Treason?!
哇哦 哇哦 伙计 冷静点 冷静
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa, boy. Easy. Easy.
是Anna公主的马 她发生什么了么 她在哪儿
Princess Anna's horse. What happened to her? Where is she?
Anna公主遇上麻烦了
Princess Anna is in trouble.
我需要志愿者和我一起前去营救  - 我愿意
I need volunteers to go with me to find her! - I'll go.
我愿意派去两人 殿下
I volunteer two men, my Lord!
做好万全准备
Be prepared for anything,
若你们碰上了女王
And should you encounter the Queen,
了结这个冬天
You are to put an end to this winter.
明白了么
Do you understand?
所以你到底准备怎么结束这寒冬
So how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
我准备和我姐姐谈一谈
Oh, I am gonna talk to my sister.
这就是你的计划 我的冰块生意现在
That's your plan? My ice business is
都指着你和你姐的谈话了
riding on you talking to your sister.
没错
Yup.
所以 你一点都不怕她么
So you're not at all afraid of her?
为什么要害怕
Why would I be?
没错
Yeah.
我敢说Elsa是我遇到过最友善 温柔
I bet Elsa's the nicest, gentlest,
亲切的人了
Warmest person ever.
快看啊
Oh, look at that.
我被钉住了
I've been impaled.
现在怎么办
What now?
这太陡了 我只有一根绳子
It's too steep. I've only got one rope,
你又不会爬山
And you don't know how to climb mountains.
谁说的
Says who?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我要去见我的姐姐
I'm going to see my sister.
你这就是自杀
You're going to kill yourself.
别踩那儿
I wouldn't put my foot there.
你别干扰我
You're distracting me.
那儿也别
Or there.
你怎么知道Elsa就愿意见你
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
我准备屏蔽你
I'm just blocking you out cause
我要集中精神
I gotta concentrate here.
躲进山里的人
You know, most people who disappear
基本都想一个人待着吧
into the mountains want to be alone.
没人想一个人待着 可能你例外
Nobody wants to be alone. Except maybe you...
我才不是一个人 我有朋友的 记得么
I'm not alone... I have friends, remember?
你是说爱情专家
You mean the love experts?
没错 爱情专家
Yes, the love experts!
拜托告诉我 我快到了
Please tell me I'm almost there.
你有没有感觉到空气变稀薄了
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
等下
Hang on.
Sven
Hey, Sven?
我不确定能不能解决问题 但是我发现了
Not sure if this is going to solve the problem, but I found
去你们要去的地方的楼梯来着
a staircase that leads exactly where you want it to go.
太棒了 接住我
Ha ha. Thank goodness. Catch!
谢谢 就像个疯狂的信任游戏(游戏者闭上眼倒在身后人的怀中)
Thanks! That was like a crazy trust exercise.
这才是真正的冰啊 我要哭了
Now that's ice. I might cry.
尽管哭 我不会说什么的
Go ahead. I won't judge.
好吧 放轻松 过来
All right, take it easy. Come here, I gotcha.
你就在这等着吧 伙计
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
完美无瑕
Flawless.
敲门吧
Knock
敲就好了
Just knock
为什么她不敲
Why isn't she knocking...?
她会敲门不啊
Do you think she knows how to knock?
居然开了 这可真是头一次
It opened. That's a first.
你最好待在外面等着
You should probably wait out here.
什么
What?
上次我介绍男人给她认识的时候 她把一切都给冻住了
Last time I introduced her to a guy, she froze everything.
但 但这可是个用冰做成的宫殿啊
But. But... Oh come on, It's a palace made of ice.
冰就是我的生命
Ice is my life.
再见 Sven
Bye, Sven.
你也是 雪宝
You too, Olaf.
我
Me?
给我一分钟就好
Just give us a minute.
好吧
Okay.
1 2 3 4
One... two... Three... four...
Elas 是我 Anna
Elsa? It's me... Anna.
Anna
Anna?
Elsa 你看上去变了
Wow... Elsa, you look different...
变好了 这个地方
It's a good different... And this place
简直太棒了
Is amazing.
谢谢
Thank you.
我一直不知道我的力量到了什么程度
I never knew what I was capable of.
发生的一切我都很抱歉 如果我早知道
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd known...
不 没事的
No, it's okay.
你不必道歉
You don't have to apologize
但你最好赶紧离开 拜托了
But you should probably go, please.
但我才刚到这
But I just got here.
你属于阿伦黛尔
You belong in Arendelle.
你也是
So do you.
不 Anna 我属于这里
No, Anna. I belong here.
独自一人
Alone.
在这里我才是真正的自己
Where I can be who I am,
也不会伤到任何人
Without hurting anybody.
其实 关于这件事
Actually, about that...
58 59 60
58...59...60.
等等 那是什么
Wait. What is that?
你好 我叫雪宝 我喜欢温暖的抱抱
Hi, I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs.
雪宝
Olaf?
你造的我 还记得么
You built me. You remember that?
你活过来了
And you're alive?
我想是吧
Um... I think so?
它和我们小时候做的那个雪人一样
He's just like the one we built as kids.
没错
Yeah!
我们那时候多亲密啊
So we were so close.
我们还可以回到从前那样
We can be like that again.
慢点
Slow Down...
Anna
Anna!
不 回不去了
No, We can't.
再见了 Anna
Goodbye, Anna.
Elsa 等等
Elsa, wait...
不 我是在保护你
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
你不用保护我 我不害怕
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
♪Please don't shut me out again.♪
♪求你了 别再推开我♪
♪Please don't slam the door.♪
♪求你了 别再关上门♪
♪You don't have to keep your distance anymore.♪
♪你不必再保持距离♪
♪Cause for the first time in forever,♪
♪漫漫时光第一次♪
♪I finally understand.♪
♪我终于能够理解♪
♪For the first time in forever, We can fix this hand in hand.♪
♪漫漫时光第一次 我们可以携手面对♪
♪We can head down this mountain Together.♪
♪让我们一起离开这里♪
♪You don't have to live in fear.♪
♪你不必生活在恐惧中♪
♪'Cause for the first time in forever,♪
♪漫漫时光第一次♪
♪I will be right here.♪
♪我就在你身边♪
♪Anna, Please go back home.♪
♪Anna 求你回去吧♪
♪Your life awaits.♪
♪你有自己的生活♪
♪Go enjoy the sun and open up the gates.♪
♪享受阳光 打开城门♪
♪Yeah, But...♪
♪可是♪
♪I know! You mean well,♪
♪我知道你是好意♪
♪But leave me be.♪
♪但请留我在这里♪
♪Yes, I'm alone But I'm alone and Free.♪
♪独自一人 但孤独而自由♪
♪Just stay away and you'll be safe from me.♪
♪远离我就不会再被我伤害♪
♪Actually, We're not.♪
♪但并非如此♪
♪ What mean you are not♪
♪我不明白♪
♪I get the feeling you don't know?♪
♪我觉得也许你不太清楚♪
♪What do I not know?♪
♪我不清楚什么♪
♪Arendelle's in deep deep deep deep snow.♪
♪阿伦黛尔现在一片冰天雪海♪
什么
What?
你好像让永冬占据了 整个大地
You kind of set off an eternal winter... everywhere.
整个大地
Everywhere?
没关系 你可以融化这冰雪
It's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
不 我不行
No, I can't.
我不知道怎么做
I don't know how.
你当然可以
Sure you can.
我知道你可以
I know you can!
- ♪'Cause for the first time in forever,♪  - ♪I'm such a Fool! I can't be Free!♪
- ♪漫漫时光第一次♪  - ♪我为何如此天真 我注定无法自由♪
♪You don't have to be afraid.♪  - ♪No escape From the storm inside of me!
- ♪你不必再去害怕♪  - ♪注定无法逃离心中的风雪♪
- ♪We can work this out together.♪  - ♪I can't control the curse!
- ♪我们可以携手面对♪  - ♪我无法掌控这诅咒♪
♪We'll reverse the storm you've made.♪
♪我们能让暴雪消退♪
♪Anna, Please, You'll only make it worse!♪
♪Anna 求你了 你只会让事情更糟♪
- ♪Don't panic.♪  - ♪There's so much fear!♪
- ♪不要慌张♪  - ♪恐惧太强烈♪
- ♪We'll make the sun shine bright.♪  - ♪You're not safe here!♪
- ♪我们会让阳光重现♪  - ♪你在这并不安全♪
♪We can face this thing together...♪
♪我们可以携手面对♪
♪No....I can't!♪
♪不 我做不到♪
Anna 你没事吧
Anna. Are you okay?
我没事 我很好
I'm okay... I'm fine.
这是谁
Who's this?
算了 无所谓了 你们得走了
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just... You have to go.
不 我知道我们能一起找到解决的办法
No, I know we can figure this out together...
怎么做 你有什么力量阻止这冬天
How? What power do you have to stop this winter?
阻止我
To stop me?
Anna  我们该走了
Anna, I think we should go.
不 Elsa 你不走我也不会走
No. I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
不 你必须走
Yes, you are.
住手 放我们下来
Stop. Put us down!
离开这儿
Go away!
小心啊
Heads up!
小心我的下半身
Watch out for my butt!
这么把人扔出来可不算礼貌
It is not nice to throw people!
好了 好了 暴脾气
Wow, Wow, Wow feisty pants. Ok, Relax.
冷静点 冷静
Just Calm down. Calm down.
我没事
All right. I'm okay.
别理会这个雪怪就行了
Just let the snow man be.
我很冷静
I'm Calm
很好
Great.
别啊
Oh... Come on!
看吧 你把它弄生气了
Uh-oh. See. Now you made him mad!
我来引开他
I'll distract him.
你们先走
You guys go.
不不不 不是你们
No, no, not you guys.
这下变得更麻烦了
This just got a whole lot harder.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我搞定它了
I got him!
这悬崖得有一百尺吧
It's a hundred foot drop.
两百尺
It's two hundred.
你这是做什么
What's that for?
我在挖出一个支点
I'm digging a snow anchor.
那万一我们掉下去怎么办
Okay. What if we fall?
底下有二十英尺厚的白雪
There's twenty feet of fresh powder down there
就像落在枕头上一样
It'll be like landing on a pillow...
但愿
Hopefully.
好了 Anna 数到三
Okay, Anna. On three.
- 一  - 还用你来告诉我
- One... - Okay. You tell me when...
- 二  - 什么时候准备好 我生下来就准备好了 没错
- Two... - I'm ready to go...I was born ready! Yes!
淡定点
Calm down.
有树
Tree!
怎么 算了
What the... Whoa!
就这样吧
That happened.
天啦 我浑身都乱了
Ah. Ah. Man, am I out of shape.
这就对了 嘿 Anna Sven
There we go. Hey, Anna! Sven!
你们去哪了 我们把那大棉花糖完全甩掉了
Where'd ya guys go? We totally lost Marshmallow back there!
哟嘿 我们刚刚还说起了你
Hey. We were just talking about you.
说的都是好话 都是好话
All good things, all good things.
不要
No!
这样是不是没什么用
This is not making much of a difference! Is it?
雪宝
Olaf!
坚持住 伙计们
Hang in there, guys!
快点
Go Faster!
等等 怎么了
Wait, what?
Kristoff
Kristoff!
别再回来
Don't come back!
我们不会了
We won't.
你说对了 就像摔在了枕头上一样
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
雪宝
Olaf!
我的腿没有知觉了 我的腿没有知觉了
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
这是我的腿
Those are my legs.
帮个忙 抓住我的下半身
Ooh. Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
感觉好多了
Oh, That feels better.
看啊 Sven 它找到我们了
Hey, Sven! He found us.
我可爱的驯鹿宝贝儿
Who's my cute little reindeer?
别和它这么说话
Don't talk to him like that.
来
Here.
你没事吧
You okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
你的头没事吧
Um... How's your head?
我很好
I mean, It's fine. Ah... I'm good.
没事的 我头骨硬
Ha. I've got a thick skull.
我没有头骨
I don't have a skull...
或者 骨头
Or bones.
那么
So...
现在怎么办
So Now what?
怎么办呢
Now what?
该怎么办呢
Now what?!
我现在怎么办
Oooh! What am I gonna do?
她把我赶了出来 阿伦黛尔还是
She threw me out. I can't go back to
一片冰天雪地 我不能就这么回去
Arendelle with the weather like this.
而且你的冰块生意
And then there's your ice business...
不用担心我的冰块生意
Hey, hey, don't worry about my ice business...
担心下你的头发吧
Worry about your hair?!
什么
What?
我刚从崖上摔下来 你才该看看你的头发呢
I Just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
不 你的头发在变白
No, yours is turning white.
白色 那只是 什么
White? It's... what?
是因为她击中了你吧
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
看上去很糟么
Does it look bad?
不是
No.
你犹豫了
You hesitated.
不 我没有 Anna 你需要帮助 来吧
No, I didn't. Anna, you need help. Okay? Come on.
好吧 我们要去哪
Okay! Where are we going?
去见我的朋友们
To see my friends.
那些爱情专家们
The love experts?
爱情专家
Love experts?!
不用担心 他们会有解决的办法的
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我之前见他们解决过
Because I've seen them do it before.
我认为我也是个爱情专家
I like to consider myself a love expert.
集中精力 控制住
Get it together. Control it.
别去想 别去想
Don't feel. Don't feel.
别去想
Don't feel!
看呀 Sven 天空醒了
Look, Sven. The sky's awake.
你冷吗
Are you cold?
有点
A little.
等下 到这来
Wait. Come here.
我的朋友们
So, about my friends...
虽然我说是朋友 但是他们更像我的家人
Well, I say friends, they're more like family...
当我还是个孩子时 只有我和Sven相依为命
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven
是他们收留了我们
until you know, they took us in.
是吗
They did?
没错
Yeah.
我不想吓着你 但是他们有时会
I don't want to scare you, they can be
表现得不太得体
a little bit inappropriate...
然后还会很吵 非常吵
And loud... very loud...
他们有时还会很固执 还有点儿傲慢
They're also stubborn at times, And a little
还有他们很重 真的很重 所以你
Overbearing. And heavy. Really, really heavy. Which you...
但是 他们人都很好 都很善良
But You know, you okay. They're fine. They mean well.
Kristoff 他们听上去很好
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
好了 那么
Okay then...
见见我的家人吧
Meet my family.
嘿 大伙儿
Hey, guys!
他们是石头
They're rocks.
他疯了
He's crazy.
嘿 我都快认不出你了 你都长这么大了
Hey, Wow... I pretty Recognize you, What's so much weigh?
趁我引开他们的时候 你赶紧跑
I'll distract them while you run.
你们好 Sven的家人们 很高兴认识你们
Hi, Sven's family! It's nice to meet you!
因为我很爱你 Anna 你快逃
because I love you, Anna, I insist you run.
我知道你是爱情专家
I understand you're love experts!
你怎么还不跑
Why aren't you running?
好吧 我要走了
Okay. Um... I'm gonna go...
不不不 Anna 等等
No, no, no. Anna, wait!
Kristoff
Kristoff!
Kristoff回家了
Kristoff's home!
Kristoff Kristoff回家了 这都多久了
Kristoff! Kristoff's home! It's been too long!
Kristoff回家了
Kristoff's home!
等下 Kristoff
Wait? Kristoff?
哦 让我好好看看你
Oh, lemme look at you!
把衣服脱下来 我来洗
Oh, take off your clothes, Kristoff, I wash them.
不 我就这么穿着
Ah! No. I'm gonna keep my clothes on, Look.
看到你们真是太好了
It's great to see you all.
不过Pabbie爷爷去哪了
But where's grand Pabbie?
他在打盹儿呢
He's napping.
但是 看呀 我长蘑菇了
But look, I grew a mushroom.
我赢得了我的火结晶
And I earned my fire crystal.
我排出了块肾结石
I passed a kidney stone.
Kristoff 快抱抱我
Kristoff, Pick me up.
你变重了 好样的
You're getting big... Good for you.
地精 他们是地精
Trolls? They're trolls.
他带回来了个女孩儿
He's brought a girl!
他带了个女孩儿
怎么回事
What's going on?
我已经习惯"随石逐流"了
I've learned to just roll with it.
让我看看 明亮的眼睛 挺拔的鼻子 坚固的牙齿
Let me see. Bright eyes. Working nose. Strong teeth.
不错 不错 和我们的Kristoff真配
Yes, yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
等下 不是这样的
Wait. Oh. Um. No.
你们误会了 我带她过来不是因为这个
You've got the wrong idea. That's not why I brought her here.
没错 我们不是 我不是
Right. We're not. I'm not...
是因为什么事呢 亲爱的
What's the issue, dear?
你为何要躲开这样一个小伙呢
Why are you holding back from such a man?
♪Is it the clumpy way he walks?♪
♪是因为他走路的滑稽样么♪
什么
What?
♪Or the Grumpy way he talks?♪
♪或是他笨拙的说话方式♪
不
No.
♪Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped♪
♪还是他脚上这双形状怪异♪
♪weirdness of his feet?♪
♪似圆似方的丁靴♪
喂
Hey!
♪And though we know he washes well♪
♪尽管我们知道他勤于洗澡♪
♪he always ends up sorta smelly.♪
♪但是他闻起来总有些奇怪♪
♪But you'll never meet a fella who's as sensitive and sweet.♪
♪但你不会再遇到像他一样温柔又贴心的小伙了♪
确实很好 但
That's nice, but...
♪So he's a bit of a fixer upper.♪
♪他有些小问题需要解决♪
♪So he's got a few flaws.♪
♪他还有些不足之处♪
♪Like his peculiar brain, dear.♪
♪比如他那奇怪的脑子 亲爱的♪
♪His thing for the reindeer.♪
♪他对这驯鹿的迷恋
♪That outside a few of nature's laws.♪
♪有点超出了正常范围♪
♪This is not about me!♪
♪我们不是为了我的事儿过来的
♪So he's a bit of a fixer upper,♪
♪他有些小问题需要解决♪
♪But this we're certain of...♪
♪但我们确信♪
♪You can fix this fixer upper up with a little bit of love.♪
♪你可以用真爱让他变得尽善尽美♪
我们能别再说这个话题了吗
Can we just stop talking about this?!
我们真的遇上麻烦了
We've got a real, actual problem here.
我赞同 那么 告诉我 亲爱的
I'll say... So tell me dear,
♪Is it the way that he runs scared?♪
♪是他害怕的落荒而逃么
♪Or that he's socially impaired?♪
♪或是他笨手拙言不懂社交♪
♪Or that he only likes to tinkle in the Woods?♪
♪还是他喜欢在森林里随地小解♪
不用告诉我这些
I do not need to know that.
♪Are you holding back your fondness♪
♪你刻意隐瞒了你的好感♪
♪Due to his unmanly blondness?♪
♪是因为他那男子气不足的金发么♪
♪Or the way he covers up that he's the honest goods?♪
♪还是因他隐藏了内心的真善美♪
♪He's just a bit of a fixer upper.♪
♪他有些小问题需要解决♪
♪He's got a couple a' bugs.♪
♪他身上还有些臭虫♪
不 我没有
No, I don't.
♪His isolation is confirmation of♪
♪他刻意远离别人♪
♪his desperation for healing hugs.♪
♪正是他需要治愈抱抱的证明♪
♪So he's a bit of a fixer upper, But we know what to do.♪
♪他有些地方需要改正 但我们知道该怎样做♪
♪The way to fix up this fixer♪
♪让他变得尽善尽美方法就是♪
♪upper is to fix him up with you.♪
♪让他和你紧紧地联系在一起♪
停下 停下 够了
Stop it. Stop it. Stop it. Enough!
她和别人订婚了 好吗
She's engaged to someone else. Okay?!
♪So she's a bit of a fixer upper,♪
♪所以她才是问题所在♪
♪That's a minor thing.♪
♪这是个小问题♪
♪Her quote "engagement"a flex arrangement.♪
♪这个所谓的婚约 并非板上定钉♪
♪And by the way, I don't see no Ring.♪
♪而且 我也没看到订婚戒指♪
♪So she's a bit of a fixer upper,♪
♪所以她才有些小问题需要解决♪
♪Her brain's a bit betwixt.♪
♪她的想法举棋不定♪
♪Get the fiance out of the way And♪
♪只要把那个未婚夫弄出局♪
♪the whole thing will be fixed!♪
♪然后就万事大吉了♪
♪We aren't saying you can change him♪
♪我们不是说你定能改变他♪
♪'Cause people don't really change.♪
♪因为人的本性很难改变♪
We're only saying that love's a force♪
♪我们的意思是真爱至上♪
♪That's powerful and strange.♪
♪力量无边却又难以捉摸♪
♪People make bad choices if they're♪
♪疯狂 害怕 紧张的情绪♪
♪mad or scared or stressed.♪
♪总会阻止人们做出正确的选择♪
♪But throw a little love their way...♪
♪但是只要让爱照亮前路♪
♪throw a little love their way.♪
♪当爱照亮前路♪
♪And you'll bring out their best!♪
♪人们就会展现出最美好的一面♪
♪True love brings out the best!♪
真爱激发出你最好的一面♪
♪Everyone's a bit of a fixer upper,♪
♪每个人都有些小问题要解决♪
♪that's what it's all about.♪
♪事情其实简单若此♪
♪Father, sister, brother! We need each other♪
♪父母 姐妹 兄弟 我们需要彼此♪
♪to raise us up and round us out.♪
♪好变得更高 滚得更远♪
♪Everyone's a bit of a fixer upper,♪
♪每个人都有些小问题要解决♪
♪But when push comes to shove.♪
♪但是归根结底♪
♪The only fixer upper fixer that can fix a fixer upper is♪
♪解决这些问题的万能方法就是♪
♪True, True, True, True, Love♪
♪真爱万能♪
♪Love, Love, Love, True Love... True-e-e-e-e-e.♪
♪真爱永恒♪
Anna 你是否愿意Kristoff成为你的丈夫与他缔结婚约
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded...
等等 什么
Wait, what?!
你们要结婚了
You're getting married.
她浑身冰冷
She's as cold as ice.
她被施了很奇怪的魔法
There's strange magic here!
Pabbie爷爷
Grand Pabbie!
让我看看她
Come come, Bring her to me.
Anna 你有生命危险
Anna, your life is in danger.
你被你姐姐用冰击中了 冰雪留在了你的心脏内
There is ice in your heart, put there by your sister.
如果不能解除 坚冰会将你永远的封住
If not removed, to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
什么 不要
What ...? No.
但是你可以解除掉的吧
But you can remove it, Right?
我不行 对不起 Kristoff
I can not, I'm sorry Kristoff...
如果是她的脑袋的话很容易解决
If it was her head that would be easy.
但想要融化冰封的心 唯一的方法是真爱的举动
But only an act of true love can thaw a frozen heart.
真爱的举动
An act of true love?
比如一个真爱之吻
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
Anna 我们得带你回到Hans的身边
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
Hans
Hans.
带上我们 Sven
Pull us out, Sven.
雪宝 快来
Olaf! Come on.
我来了
I'm coming!
咱们去吻Hans吧
Let's go kiss Hans!
谁是Hans来着
Who is this Hans?!
我们是前来寻找Anna公主的
We are here to find Princess Anna.
保持警惕
Be on guard,
但不要伤害到女王陛下
but no harm is to come to the Queen.
明白了么
Do you understand?
是的 殿下
Yes, sir.
女王在那
The Queen.
就在上面
Up there!
赶紧来
Come on!
不 求你了
No, Please.
快走开
Stay away!
射击 射击
Fire! Fire
抓住她 抓住她
Get her! Get her!
Elsa女王
Queen Elsa!
别成为他们所畏惧的那个怪物
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
不 我干了些什么
No...What have I done?
你为什么要带我到这来
Why did you bring me here?
我不能让他们杀了你
I couldn't just let them kill you.
但是我对阿伦黛尔来说是个威胁
But I'm a danger to Arendelle.
让Anna过来
Get Anna.
Anna还没有回来
Anna has not returned...
你能停下这寒冬
If you would just stop the winter,
让夏日回归么 拜托了
bring back summer... please.
你还不明白么
Don't you see...
我不行
I can't.
你得让他们放我走
You have to tell them to let me go.
我尽力而为
I will do what I can.
再坚持一下
Just hang in there.
伙计 再快点
Come on, buddy, faster!
我们城堡见
I'll meet you guys at the castle!
注意隐蔽 Olaf
Stay out of sight, Olaf!
我会的
I will!
你好啊
Hello
是Anna公主
It's Princess Anna!
你会没事的吧
Are you g-gonna be okay?
不用担心我
Don't worry about me.
- Anna 你让我们担心死了  - 公主殿下
- Anna! Oh, you had us worried sick. - My Lady.
让她暖和起来然后去找Hans王子 立刻去
Get her warm and find Prince Hans, immediately.
知道了 谢谢你
We will. Thank you.
确保她的安全
Make sure she's safe!
我准备再回去找Anna公主
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
你不能再去冒险出去了
You cannot risk going out there again.
如果她发生了什么意外
If anything happens to her...
如果你发生了什么意外呢
If anything happens to the Princess,
现在阿黛伦尔只有你了
you are all Arendelle has left.
他在这里 Hans王子
He's in here. Prince Hans.
Anna
Anna.
你好冷
You're so cold.
Hans 吻我
Hans, you have to kiss me.
什么
What?
现在 立刻
Now. Now.
我们先回避一下
We'll give you two some privacy.
外面发生了什么
What happened out there?
Elsa的魔法击中了我
Elsa struck me with her powers.
你说她绝不会伤害你
You said she'd never hurt you.
我错了
I was wrong.
Anna
Anna?
她冻住了我的心 只有真爱之举才能救我
She froze my heart and only an act of true love can save me.
一个真爱之吻
A true love's kiss.
Anna
Oh, Anna...
要是真有人那么爱你就好了
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
什么
What?
可你说过你爱我
You said you did.
做为第十三顺位的王子
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
我根本不可能取得王位
I didn't stand a chance. I knew...
我只能娶一位王位继承人
I'd have to marry into the throne somewhere...
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
作为继承人 Elsa当然是最佳选择
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
但是没有人能够靠近她
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
但是你
But you...
Hans
Hans?
你是如此渴求爱情
You were so desperate for love,
居然愿意就这么嫁给我
You were willing to marry me, just like that.
我本打算 在我们结婚后
I figured, after we married,
让Elsa发生点意外
I'd haveto stage a little accident for Elsa.
Hans 不 别说了
Hans. No, stop.
但是她作茧自缚
But then she doomed herself,
而你蠢到追了出去
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
求你了
Please.
接下来只需要杀掉Elsa
All that's left now is to kill Elsa
让一切恢复原状
and bring back summer.
你根本不是Elsa的对手
You're no match for Elsa.
不 是你不是Elsa的对手
No, you're no match for Elsa
而我会成为英雄
I, on the other hand, am the hero
救阿伦黛尔水火之中
who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
你不会得逞的
You won't get away with this.
我已经得逞了
Oh, I already have.
来人啊 帮帮我
Please, somebody help.
帮帮我 帮帮我
Please, please!
这里每分每秒都在变得更冷
It's getting colder by the minute.
如果我们不做点什么
If we don't do something soon,
我们都会冻死在这
We'll all freeze to death.
Hans王子
Prince Hans.
Anna公主她
Princess Anna is...
死了
Dead.
什么
What...?
发生了什么
What happened to her?
她被Elsa女王害死了
She was killed by Queen Elsa.
她的亲姐姐
Her own sister.
至少她死在我的怀里之前
At least we got to say our marriage vows...
我们宣誓结为夫妻
before she died in my arms.
毋庸置疑
There can be no doubt now,
Elsa女王就是个怪物 我们的生命安全都受到了威胁
Queen Elsa is a monster and we are all in grave danger.
Hans王子 王国只能指望你了
Prince Hans, Arendelle looks to you.
怀着万分沉重的心情
With a heavy heart,
我宣判Elsa女王叛国
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason
处以死刑
and sentence her to death.
快一点
Hurry Up!
她很危险 动作快点 也小心点
She's dangerous. Move quickly and be careful.
门打不开 它被冻住了
It won't open! It forzen charge
怎么了 伙计
What is it, buddy?
小心点
Hey, watch it.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我不明白你这么说话什么意思
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
快停下 放我下来
Ah! Stop it! Put me down!
不 Sven 我们不能回去
No, Sven! We're not going back!
她和她的真爱在一起
She's with her true love.
这是
What the...
Anna
Anna!
救命
Help.
Anna
Anna.
不要
Oh no.
雪宝 雪宝 赶紧离开那儿
Olaf? Olaf. Get away from there.
所以这就是热吗
So this is heat...
我太喜欢了
I love it.
但是最好别碰
Ooh! But don't touch it!
Hans去哪了
So, where's Hans?
你们吻过了么
What happened to your kiss?
我看错他了
I was wrong about him.
他不是我的真爱
It wasn't true love.
结果我们还大费周章地跑回来
Huh. But we ran all the way here?
拜托了 雪宝 你不能待在这
Please Olaf, you can't stay here,
你会融化的
you'll melt.
在你被真爱拯救之前
I am not leaving here until we find
我是不会离开这的
some other act of true love to save you.
你有什么主意吗
Do you happen to have any ideas?
我甚至都不知道什么是爱
I don't even know what love is.
这没问题 我懂 爱就是
That's okay, I do... Love is...
把他人的需要看得比你自己的更重要 比如
putting someone else's needs before yours, like, you know,
Kristoff带你回到Hans的身边
how Kristoff brought you back here
然后永远的离开你
to Hans and left you forever.
Kristoff爱我
Kristoff loves me?
看来你的确对爱一无所知
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
雪宝 你在融化
Olaf, you're melting.
有的人值得我融化
Some people are worth melting for.
只不过时机也许不太对
Just maybe not right this second.
别担心 我来搞定
Don't worry, I've got it!
我们一定可以撑住的
We're going to get through...
等等 我看到了什么
Oh, wait. Hang on. I'm getting something.
是Kristoff和Sven
It's Kristoff and Sven!
他们回来了
They're coming back this way.
真的吗
They-they are?
他跑得可真快
Wow, he's really moving fast.
我想我错了
Huh... I guess I was wrong.
Kristoff对你的爱还不足以
I guess Kristoff doesn't love
让他永远离开你
you enough to leave you behind.
帮帮我 雪宝 拜托了
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
不不不 你必须
No, no, no, no, no.
你必须呆在火炉旁保持温暖
You need tostay by the fire and keep warm.
我必须去见Kristoff
I need to get to Kristoff.
为什么
Why?
我懂为什么了
Oh, oh, oh, I know why.
你那真爱之举就靠他了
There's your act of true love right there,
正像个英勇无畏的王者
Riding across the fjords like a valiant,
穿过海湾 快去吧
pungent reindeer king! Come on!
小心点
Look out!
回来这里
Back this way!
我们被困住了
We're trapped.
滑下去 Anna
Slide, Anna.
太棒了
We made it!
冲冲冲
Go, Go, Go, Go...
加油 伙计 再快点
Come on, buddy, faster.
Kristoff
Kristoff!
继续走
Keep going.
Kristoff
Kristoff!
Sven
Sven!
好孩子
Good boy.
Kristoff
Kristoff.
Anna
Anna!
Elsa
Elsa.
你走不掉的
You can't run from this!
照顾好我妹妹
Just take care of my sister.
你妹妹
Your sister?
她从山上回来时虚弱又冰冷
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
她说你把她的心冻住了
She said you froze her heart.
我试着去救她 但是已经太迟了
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
她的皮肤结冰了 头发变得雪白
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white...
你的妹妹死了
Your sister is dead
都是因为你
because of you.
不
No!
Kristoff
Kristoff?
Anna
Anna!
Elsa
Elsa?
住手
No!
Anna
Anna!
Anna 不不不
Oh, Anna... no... no,
求你了 不要
please no.
Anna
Anna.
Anna?
Anna
Elsa
Oh, Elsa.
你为了我牺牲了自己
You sacrificed yourself for me?
我爱你
I love you.
真爱之举融化了冰封的心
An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart.
爱能够融化
Love... will thaw...
没错 就是爱
Love... Of course.
Elsa
Elsa?
是爱
Love.
我就知道你能行
I knew you could do it.
太棒了 这是我一生中最好的一天
Hands down, this is the best day of my life...
可能也是最后一天了
and quite possibly the last.
雪宝
Olaf,
坚持下 小家伙
hang on, little guy.
我自己的雪云
Hey, my own personal flurry.
Anna
Anna?
但是她冻住了你的心
But she froze your heart.
这儿有冰冷的心的人只有你
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
我会把这个恶棍遣送回国的
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
到时候看看他那
We shall see what his twelve big
十二个哥哥会怎么处置他
brothers think of his behavior.
阿伦黛尔感谢你 大人
Arendelle thanks you, my Lord.
不可理喻
This is unacceptable.
我是无辜的 我不过是太害怕了
I am innocent. I'm a victim of fear.
我的心理受到了创伤
I've been traumatized.
我脖子好疼
Ow! My neck hurts.
我要见医生
Is there a doctor that I could see.
不 我要求觐见女王
No,I demand to see the Queen!
我有女王的旨意
I have a message from the Queen.
从今日起至永远 我国
Arendelle will henceforth and forever
都不会再与猥琐屯有任何商业往来
no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown.
是维斯顿 维斯顿
Weselton. It's Weselton!
- 快来 快来  - 好吧 好吧
- Come on. Come on. Come on. - Come on! Ow, Okay, Okay...
有柱子
Pole.
对不起
Oops. So Sorry.
好了 我们到了
Okay. Okay. Here we are.
我欠你一个雪橇
I owe you a sled.
说真的
Are you serious?
没错 而且这是最新款
Yes. And it's the latest model.
不 我不能接受
No. I can't accept this...
你必须接受 不得退换 女王的旨意
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
她正式任命你为
She's named you the official
阿伦黛尔冰块特派员
Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
什么 根本没那种东西吧
What? That's not a thing.
当然有
Sure it is.
而且还有个专门的杯托
And it even has a cup holder
你喜欢么
Do you like it?
喜欢
Like it?
我爱死了
I love it...
我真想亲你一下
I could kiss you!
我想 我希望 我
I could. I mean I'd like to. I'd...
我可以吗 不是 你愿意吗
May I? We me... I mean, may we?
等等 什么
Wait, what?
我愿意
We may.
夏日
Summer!
你好
Hello.
准备好了么
Are you ready?
门又打开了 太好了
I like the open gates.
不会再关上了
We are never closing them again.
什么 Elsa 它们确实很漂亮
What? Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful,
但是我不会
but you know I don't ska...
来吧 你能做到的
Come on, you can do it!
小心点 驯鹿来了
Look out! Reindeer come through.
嘿 大伙们
Hey, guys.
电波字幕组  诚心诚译
官方网站:dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组
欢迎您的加入